hi there i'm caitlin mcdonald with the
social speak network and today we're
going to be talking about the six
tips for successful healthcare marketing
campaigns
digital marketing has become the new
wave of
healthcare marketing with growing
competition in the healthcare industry
it's important to stay top of digital
marketing and keep
your organization at the forefront of
change
today the competition is getting tougher
and patients are getting
smarter many of them even turn to google
for quick answers for health related
concerns
if you want to get more customers in
your door then you need to get in front
of your audience and have a solid
presence online otherwise someone else
will
this is why it's important to have a
healthcare marketing plan
so you can reach potential and existing
patients at the best time
ever wonder what it takes to create a
successful healthcare marketing campaign
we are going to review six tips that you
can incorporate
right today number one know
your target audience a successful
healthcare marketing campaign starts
with knowing your
audience and what they value so to
produce great results you need to
first have a well-defined persona
profile
so vividly picture
what it is that you want to attract to
your office
what matters most to them what questions
do they have
just carefully and precisely figure out
who this target audience is
also identify if there are any decision
makers that this audience
turns to you want your message to both
appeal to the target audience
as well as anybody who's going to help
them make that decision
to turn to you and your practice
the second tip is to combine healthcare
and social media today social media
isn't just a place for family and
friends to stay in touch
people also use them to promote their
business and reach their audience
the power of social media extends to all
industries
including healthcare social media
platforms like twitter
facebook instagram linkedin even
pinterest
can help you reach a wider audience and
connect with your followers
it also will help you drive traffic and
leads to your website
so now that you know who your target
audience is it'll be
easier for you you to reach your key
audience
by tapping into online communities and
sharing health information
um so keep in mind though that each
platform has its own voice and its own
audience when you create social media
content make sure that that
message is tailored towards the
different audiences and
channels so for example if you work with
young adults
you might find tick-tock or instagram's
a great way to connect with them
but potentially the decision makers that
drive them to
come into your door and schedule that
consultation could be on linkedin
or on facebook so you have to
be able to weigh the pros and cons of
each network
as well as figure out what type of
messaging maybe it's case studies that
you're putting on linkedin
but not really publishing so many of
them on facebook
so you need to figure out what that
content strategy is
for each of the networks and stay
consistent with it
the next item is to make
wellness a lot more fun health and
wellness is a serious topic
but that doesn't mean that your campaign
should be boring and uninspiring
so let's take cues from united
healthcare successful
healthcare marketing campaign we dare
you united healthcare created
an interactive campaign that dares
people to make one small change to live
healthier lives
and document it on social media each
month there were new challenges and
quizzes aimed at inspiring people to
live a healthier lifestyle
the multi-awarded we dare you campaign
not only
led to healthier habits but it also
fostered that interactive online
community
of loyalists the next one
is to an establish excuse me to
establish
an email marketing campaign email
marketing is an effective means of
transmitting
messages to your current and prospective
audience
in fact studies suggest that email
marketing
is 40 times more effective
at acquiring new customers compared to
facebook and
twitter when done right it can help you
grow your audience
grow your practice and reach a larger
amount
of target patients
with email marketing your audience is
openly receptive
and it's relatively low cost compared to
spending thousands of dollars
each month in advertising campaigns
typically however we make sure that on
any request a consultation form
or form on your website there's a check
mark that somebody can select to receive
marketing information
from you and your practice this opens up
the doors
to not only boost the roi of the current
campaigns that you have
but also stay top of mind with those
individuals
who maybe wanted to schedule a
consultation
but couldn't quite find the time to pick
up the phone and get it on the books
now the fifth one is to google yourself
studies suggest that physicians and
other medical practitioners
receive up to 45 of new patients through
referrals
though most patients would consider the
referral of other doctors families and
friends
a majority of them will also reach out
to google
search on google and check your repert
reputation before booking an appointment
the survey
revealed 60 of patients wouldn't book an
appointment with a medical practitioner
that had bad reviews so google yourself
now it might seem silly but it's
actually pretty important
by running a quick google search on
yourself you'll have a good idea of how
your practice looks from a consumer's
perspective
and you'll know where to start creating
your digital strategy
you also want to make sure that all the
information about you
is correct and updated if you do
unearth some negative results
try and take the post down or at least
reply to that comment with
a thoughtful kind response um
we always recommend at least trying to
take that conversation
back offline and so that you can resolve
it with that patient
if nothing else it shows that you are
taking the time to really care for your
patients
on and offline before and after their
appointments
and the last one is to be a source of
health
helpful information in today's digital
world
most people's inclination would be open
to
be to open up a browser in google and
research about their
own or their loved ones conditions with
so many people turning to the internet
for answers
it's important to make on healthcare
marketing
as helpful as possible for your practice
we recommend thinking about the top
questions that people often ask you
before they make a decision to come in
when they're making the decision to come
in
and at those appointments and follow-up
appointments
from here you can record yourself or
another
physician or specialist answering those
questions
so then you will have the transcript
you'll have a video and you will have
social media posts as well as content to
include in newsletters
that specifically answer that question
with the rise of mobile searches on
google we're finding more and more
searches
being for long-form questions and so by
making content that fits in with that
mold you actually are better positioning
yourself
not only to serve your patient but also
to be
ranked more highly for google so i hope
that these tips have been helpful for
you
again these were the six tips for a
successful healthcare marketing campaign
again my name is caitlin mcdonald i'm
here with the social speak network
and if you have any questions about how
to
best manage your marketing campaigns for
your healthcare practice
we would love to chat head on over to
socialspeaknetwork.com
click that free consultation button and
we'll get a call scheduled
thanks so much and i'll see you next
time